<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Quixotic Quant</title>
    <link>/categories/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Quixotic Quant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of debate: A bird&#39;s-eye on migration</title>
      <link>/post/birdseye/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/birdseye/</guid>
      <description>A high-level response This post is a follow-on from my first post on this topic, where I suggested that an alternative statistic “Physically Present Population” suggested Australia’s migration rate might be overstated by “Net Overseas Migration” and the derived “Estimated Resident Population” might also be frothy as well. I’m glad that the piece had the intended effect, and provoked two published responses from Dr. Cameron Murray and Leith van Onselen. which I’ll address in some detail later on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Million: Is Australia&#39;s migration rate actually high?</title>
      <link>/post/the-missing-million/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-missing-million/</guid>
      <description>It’s time that someone took a proper tilt at Australia’s high migration rate. No, I don’t mean like Dick Smith, splashing millions on an advertising campaign arguing that such a high rate is unsustainable and that we should return down to previous levels. I mean taking a few hours with the data source to figure out whether Australia’s migration rate actually is any higher than it was at previous levels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>