<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quixotic Quant</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Quixotic Quant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering the Part-Time Population: Speed and Seasonality</title>
      <link>/post/movement-trends-speed-and-seasonality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/movement-trends-speed-and-seasonality/</guid>
      <description>This post is a follow-on from my second post on migration, where I made the proposition that the true level-shift which warranted discussion was actually in international mobility, rather than Australia’s inward migration. I described conceptually how the definition of migration (which I’d discussed in detail in my first post) would inevitably lead to Australia registering a high migration rate while mobility was increasing globally, since we were naturally more likely to be a long-trip destination than a short-trip destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of debate: A bird’s-eye on migration</title>
      <link>/post/the-state-of-debate-a-bird-s-eye-on-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-state-of-debate-a-bird-s-eye-on-migration/</guid>
      <description>This post is a follow-on from my first post on this topic. In that post I pointed to a couple of alternative statistics which can be derived from ABS data, including “Net Overseas Movements”, and “Physically Present Population”. I suggested Australia’s migration rate might be substantially overstated by “Net Overseas Migration” (NOM), and the derived “Estimated Resident Population” (ERP) might also look bit frothy, or even a million people frothy according to ABS data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Million: Is Australia&#39;s migration rate actually high?</title>
      <link>/post/the-missing-million/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-missing-million/</guid>
      <description>It’s time that someone took a proper tilt at Australia’s high migration rate. No, I don’t mean like Dick Smith, splashing millions on an advertising campaign arguing that such a high rate is unsustainable and that we should return down to previous levels. I mean taking a few hours with the data source to figure out whether Australia’s migration rate actually is any higher than it was at previous levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Quixotic Quant Blog</title>
      <link>/post/opening-remarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/opening-remarks/</guid>
      <description>I think it’s worth a short post to explain where the name ‘Quixotic Quant’ came from.
Quixotic This word sums up my intent to use this blog to ‘tilt at windmills’, in the metaphorical style of Don Quixote. By ‘tilt’ I mean it as it’s meant in jousting. Take a direct charge against an idea and try to topple it, or at least have an exciting clash of intellectual arms, and hopefully have some fun and amuse onlookers while you’re at it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Author</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Aidan Morrison Originally trained as a physicist, I think these days I&amp;rsquo;m best described as an entrepreneur, with interests in data analytics, military technology, and hospitality.
Born and raised in Launceston, Tasmania, I attended Launceston Church Grammar School before moving to Canberra to study at the Australian National University. I completed a Bachelor of Science with First Class Honours. My majors were in Physics and Theoretical Physics, and my thesis was in Theoretical Particle Physics, on Kaon Decay in the Generation Model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>aidan@trendlock.com.au @QuixoticQuant</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>