<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ausecon on Quixotic Quant</title>
    <link>/tags/ausecon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ausecon on Quixotic Quant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ausecon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Million Part II: Bringing the Boomers back from Bali</title>
      <link>/post/the-missing-million/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-missing-million/</guid>
      <description>This post is a follow-on from my first post on this topic, where I suggested that an alternative statistic “Physicaly Present Population” suggested Australia’s migration rate might be overstated by “Net Overseas Migration.
That particular tilt certainly had the intended effect, and provoked quite a response. I’ve had plenty of tweets, as well as direct emails and phone calls from experienced people wanting to discuss with me the findings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Million: Is Australia&#39;s migration rate actually high?</title>
      <link>/post/the-missing-million/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-missing-million/</guid>
      <description>It’s time that someone took a proper tilt at Australia’s high migration rate. No, I don’t mean like Dick Smith, splashing millions on an advertising campaign arguing that such a high rate is unsustainable and that we should return down to previous levels. I mean taking a few hours with the data source to figure out whether Australia’s migration rate actually is any higher than it was at previous levels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>