<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on Quixotic Quant</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on Quixotic Quant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovering the Part-Time Population: Speed and Seasonality</title>
      <link>/post/movement-trends-speed-and-seasonality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/movement-trends-speed-and-seasonality/</guid>
      <description>This post is a follow-on from my second post on migration, where I made the proposition that the true level-shift which warranted discussion was actually in international mobility, rather than Australia’s inward migration. I described conceptually how the definition of migration (which I’d discussed in detail in my first post) would inevitably lead to Australia registering a high migration rate while mobility was increasing globally, since we were naturally more likely to be a long-trip destination than a short-trip destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state of debate: A bird’s-eye on migration</title>
      <link>/post/the-state-of-debate-a-bird-s-eye-on-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-state-of-debate-a-bird-s-eye-on-migration/</guid>
      <description>This post is a follow-on from my first post on this topic. In that post I pointed to a couple of alternative statistics which can be derived from ABS data, including “Net Overseas Movements”, and “Physically Present Population”. I suggested Australia’s migration rate might be substantially overstated by “Net Overseas Migration” (NOM), and the derived “Estimated Resident Population” (ERP) might also look bit frothy, or even a million people frothy according to ABS data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Missing Million: Is Australia&#39;s migration rate actually high?</title>
      <link>/post/the-missing-million/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-missing-million/</guid>
      <description>It’s time that someone took a proper tilt at Australia’s high migration rate. No, I don’t mean like Dick Smith, splashing millions on an advertising campaign arguing that such a high rate is unsustainable and that we should return down to previous levels. I mean taking a few hours with the data source to figure out whether Australia’s migration rate actually is any higher than it was at previous levels.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>